'Til death do us part.
Mr. & Mrs. Smith is a action, comedy, drama film directed by Doug Liman.
A husband and wife struggle to keep their marriage alive until they
realize they are both secretly working as assassins.
Now, their respective assignments require them to kill each other.
John Smith, played by Brad Pitt.
Jane Smith, played by Angelina Jolie.
Eddie, played by Vince Vaughn.
Benjamin Danz, played by Adam Brody.
Jasmine, played by Kerry Washington.
Father, played by Keith David.
Smith is a 2005 American action comedy film directed by
Doug Liman and written by Simon Kinberg.
The film stars Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie as a bored upper middle class married couple, who are surprised to learn that they are
assassins belonging to competing agencies, leading to them trying to kill each other in order to protect themselves.
Incidentally, the filming marked the beginning of Pitt and Jolie's real-life personal relationship,
which would result in a romantic relationship, marriage, and children from 2005 to 2016.
Smith was released in the United States on June 10, 2005, and received mixed reviews from critics,
who praised Pitt and Jolie's performances and chemistry but criticized the screenplay.
Nevertheless, the film was a commercial success, grossing $487.3 million
worldwide and becoming the seventh highest-grossing film of 2005.
In 2024, a television series of the same name loosely inspired by the film premiered on Amazon Prime Video, starring Donald Glover and Maya Erskine as two
strangers paired up as spies and posing as a married couple; producer Arnon Milchan is the only cast or crew member returning from the original film.
The film explores themes of assassin, bomb, hitman, marriage crisis, gun.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and intense.